Register of the Chang Hsin-Hai Papers, 1936-1976.
Hoover Institution Archives
Chang Hsin-Hai Papers,
1936-1976.
77045
Chang, Hsin-hai, 1898-
19 manuscript boxes (8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, clippings, and printed matter, relating to Chinese foreign relations with the United States, 1941-1971; Chinese efforts to gain public support in the United States, 1941-1945; Chinese history; and World War II. Includes correspondence of Siang Mei Rosalynde Chang.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Literature.; Propaganda, Chinese--United States.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--China.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.; China.; China--Foreign relations--Czechoslovakia.; China--Foreign relations--Poland.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; Czechoslovakia.; Czechoslovakia--Foreign relations--China.; Poland.; Poland--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Foreign relations--China.
Biographical Note.
1900, June 24 Born, Shanghai, China
1916-1918 Student, Tsinghua College, Peking, China
1919 A.B., Johns Hopkins University
1920 A.M., Harvard University
1921 Attache, Chinese Delegation, Washington Disarmament Conference
1923 Ph.D. in English literature, Harvard University
1926 Professor, and Chairman of English Literature, Peking National University
1927 Married to Siang-mei Han
1928-1933 Director of European and American Department, Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs
1933-1937 Chinese Minister Plenipotentiary to Portugal, Poland, and Czechoslovakia
1937-1940 Professor of Western Literature, University of Nanking
1941-1945 Lecturer in U.S.A. on Chinese war effort
1943 Special Assistant to Foreign Minister T. V. Soong
1944 Author: Chiang Kai-Shek, Asia's Man of Destiny
1947-1948 Director, Chinese United Nations Association
1948 Author: Letters From a Chinese Diplomat
1951-1953 Research Professor, Long Island University
1956-1969 Professor, Farleigh Dickinson University
1956 Author: The Fabulous Concubine
1958 Author: Within the Four Seas
1966 Author: America and China, a New Approach to Asia
1972, December 7 Died, Shanghai, China
Series Description
- Correspondence, 1936-1976. (Box No. 1-6.)
  Arranged alphabetically.
- Speeches and Writings, 1942-1966. (Box No. 7-15.)
  Drafts, research notes, radio scripts, and book reviews relating to Chang Hsin-hai's writings, arranged alphabetically by title.
- Subject File, 1941-1972. (Box No. 16-17.)
  Reports, conference papers, notes, clippings, and printed matter arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Miscellany. (Box No. 18-19.)
  Unprocessed clippings and reprints of articles.
Container List
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1936-1976
  - Unidentified (Box 1.)
  - Abend, Hallett, 1944-1946
  - Accolla, Peter S., 1971
  - Ackerman, Phyllis, 1962
  - Adams, W. G. G., 1942
  - Ambrosoli, Marija, 1942
  - Ancell, Mrs. B. L., 1942
  - Armstrong, Hamilton, 1944
  - Atkinson, Henry A., 1949
  - Baehne, G. W., 1943
  - Barker, Alexander, 1945
  - Beauchamp, Ellen, 1942
  - Becker, Russell, 1970
  - Bedell, Muriel, 1942
  - Berle, A. A., 1947
  - Berliz, Paul O., 1949
  - Besser, Clade von, 1945
  - Blair, Sara G., 1942
  - Bloss, Frank, 1942
  - Boddy, Manchester, 1942
  - Boney, Alice, 1960
  - Bonsen, Victor, 1941
  - Booker, H. L., 1944
  - Borker, Edith, 1942
  - Bowman, M. L., 1942
  - Branch, Mrs. Norman, 1944
  - Brendzell, Marilyn, 1971
  - Bricca, Dolores, 1942
  - Briggs, Ernest, 1942
  - British Information Service, 1942
  - Buck, Pearl S., 1942-1961
  - Buist, Ruth, 1972
  - Button, A. Ronald, 1944
  - Capozzi, Roy, 1964
  - Cadebear, Florence E., 1945
  - Calhoun, Adele, 1942
  - Campbell, Mary, 1942
  - Carberry, J. E., 1942
  - Chadwick, I. E., 1945
  - Chadwick, Margaret Lee, 1944
  - Chambers, Harry M., 1942
  - Chambers, Lenoir, 1946
  - Chang, Andrew, 1964
  - Chang, C. K., 1946-1963
  - Chang, C. L., 1947
  - Chang, C. S., 1948
  - Chang, Chi-tai, 1942-1946
  - Chang, P. F., 1973-1975
  - Chang, P. H., 1944-1976
  - Chang, Mrs. Siang-mei Rosalynde, 1943-1950 (Box 2.)
  - Chang, Shan-chi, 1943
  - Chiang, Kai-shek, Madame, 1944
  - Chen, N., 1969
  - Chien, Hou, 1970
  - Chien, T. S., 1946
  - Chow, P. Y., 1944
  - Chu, Y. H., 1948
  - Church, Frank, 1971
  - Church, Genevieve, 1942
  - Claque, J. W., 1941
  - Cochran, Steven, 1945
  - Coleman, George, 1942
  - Colon, Tom, 1943
  - Connell, Abe, 1941
  - Coppello, Kappeyne van de, 1948
  - Craft, Jason, 1942
  - Crammer, Helen, 1969
  - Crane, John O., 1961
  - Crocker, Leua P., 1942
  - Crowe, Anne P., 1944
  - Culbertson, Paul T., 1942
  - Dagleisch, M. E., 1942 (Box 3.)
  - Danton, George H., 1941
  - David, M. I., 1945
  - Davidson, Elizabeth, 1943
  - Davidson, Robert J., 1942
  - Davis, Bette, 1942
  - Day, R. M., 1948
  - Dell, John, 1942
  - Deuser, Lewis, 1947
  - Dewey, John, 1943
  - Dilley, Arthur Urbane, 1955
  - Dilley, Porter, 1942
  - Dimmitt, S. Grace, 1942
  - Dixon, Charles R., 1942
  - Doria, Anthony N., 1970
  - Doyle, James C., 1944
  - Dreiser, Theodor, 1945
  - Dufus, Robert L., 1962
  - Durrand, Odette, 1942
  - Durant, Ariel and Will, 1944-1963
  - Dyer, Josephine, 1944
  - East, N., 1948
  - Eaton, Cyrus, 1956
  - Eaton, Joseph E., n.d.
  - Elex, Mrs. Clark R., 1942
  - Elmo, Ann, 1948
  - Esfmoff, A., 1949
  - Faerber, Paul, 1949
  - Fairbank, Alfred, n.d.
  - Farrar, John, 1941
  - Feakins, William B., 1943-1944
  - Feng, Chanson, n.d.
  - Fier, Jack, 1942
  - Fischer, Martin, 1948
  - Fisher, Melthy, 1955
  - Fisher, Ray Wall, 1942
  - Fitzgerald, C. P., 1956
  - Folger, Herschel, 1941
  - Ford, Roy E., 1944
  - Forman, Henry James, 1947
  - Forster, L., 1941
  - Freuchen, Peter, 1953
  - Fulbright, J. W., 1964-1971
  - Fuller, Ruth, 1942
  - Gallagher, P., 1942
  - Gerson, Perceval T., 1942, 1944
  - Getts, Clark H., 1943
  - Gray, Robert, 1942
  - Green, Alan, 1944
  - Greenleaf, Mary, 1942
  - Grier, Madeline, n.d.
  - Griest, Rebecca, 1962
  - Goodnow, Marc N., 1941
  - Griffin, David, 1942
  - Hagen, Jessie Scott, 1942
  - Hammarskjold, Dag, 1953
  - Han, C. K., 1949
  - Han, G. C., 1942
  - Han, H. J., n.d.
  - Han, Hsiang-pu, 1951, 1975
  - Han, Hsiang-yo, n.d.
  - Han, Hsing-lan, n.d.
  - Han, Li-wu, 1936-1941
  - Hadden, Frances Roots, 1973
  - Hart, A. L., 1946
  - Hauser, Lewis, 1942
  - Hawley, W. M., 1960
  - Heathcote, Mary, 1968, 1971
  - Heide, J. A., 1953
  - Heilman, Elizabeth, 1953
  - Henning, R. F., 1942
  - Herman, Doritt, 1944
  - Heyman, Valeska, 1942
  - Ho, Georgette, 1948
  - Hoover, Ann, n.d.
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1945-1946
  - Horn, Phyllis, 1942
  - Hossain, Syud, 1943
  - Howard, Eric, 1942
  - Howe, Quincy, 1942
  - Hoyt, Sarah Lee, 1942
  - Hsia, C. L., 1942
  - Hu, Shih, 1941
  - Hueston, Frederick, 1942
  - Hull, Cordell, 1944
  - Hull, Warren, 1949
  - Hurlblut, Harold, 1942
  - Hutchins, Dr., 1967
  - Irish, Mrs. Leiland, 1945 (Box 4.)
  - Jaffe, William B., 1943-1944
  - Javits, Jacob, 1971
  - Jensen, Elsie, 1948
  - Jose, M. C., 1942
  - Jong, J., 1966
  - Jordan-Smith, Paul, 1944
  - Joy, Marguerite, 1942
  - Kai, C. Ju, 1946
  - Kallen, Horace, n.d.
  - Karter, Madeline, 1962
  - Keator, M. C., 1942
  - Kennedy, Edward, 1971
  - Kages, Don H., 1942
  - Kleinschmidt, R. B. von, 1941, 1944
  - Klems, Iola, 1942
  - Kiernan, Edmund, 1942
  - Killion, Gerald, 1949
  - Knight, Leonore, 1942
  - Knox, William F., 1953
  - Koch, William de, 1944
  - Koeber, Hans von, 1942
  - Korda, Michael, 1967
  - Kuan, C. W., 1942
  - Kuffner, Lieutenant de, 1942
  - Kuiltel, Luise Rainier, 1957
  - Kung, H. H., 1948
  - Kuylenstierna, Krister, 1954-1976
  - Kwan, S. T., n.d.
  - LaFargue, Thomas E., 1942, 1944
  - Lan, T. K., n.d.
  - Langsdorf, W. B., 1942
  - Lee, Dai-ming, 1946
  - Lee, S. M., 1949
  - Lee, Sze Nancy, 1969
  - Leonard, W. S., 1958
  - Lewis, E. R., 1942
  - Lu, Chieh, 1942
  - Ludwick, Kathleen, 1942
  - Ludwig, Mrs. Emil, 1943
  - Lytton, Bart, 1942
  - Lynch, Howard, 1942
  - Lynch, Thomas, 1942
  - Li, Chien-len, 1975
  - Lillenthal, Phillip, 1944
  - Lindsey, Ben, 1942
  - Link, Professor, 1966
  - Lissauer, Norman, 1942
  - Liu, H. S., 1948
  - Liu, S. S., 1969
  - Liu, Yu-whu, 1941
  - Lowe, Albert, 1942
  - MacBeth, Hugh E., 1942
  - MacDavid, H. M., 1942
  - Maizlish, Harry, 1942
  - Malone, Thomas, 1941
  - Mander, Miles, 1941-1943
  - Matoon, Paul F., 1944
  - McClave, Elizabeth, 1944
  - McCormick, Ken, 1943
  - McGovern, George, 1971
  - McIntosh, Frances, 1942
  - McKelvey, Raymond, 1942
  - McLaughlin, Milicent, 1943-1944
  - McNaughton, Jane, 1942
  - McNitt, Rollin, 1942
  - Meyer, Agnes, 1961-1967
  - Meyer, Lois, 1943
  - Miller, Allan, 1949
  - Miller, Henry, 1957-1964
  - Miller, M. M., 1944
  - Miller, Simon S., 1948
  - Ministry of Foreign Afairs, n.d.
  - Mitchell, Ruth Crawford, 1947
  - Moltke, Davida, 1966
  - Montgomery, Mary, 1942
  - Moody, A. R., 1942
  - Morgan, Frieda, 1950
  - Mueller, John H., 1943
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1965
  - Murphy, Lawrence, 1945
  - Murphy, Leonore, 1943
  - Nash, E. T., 1942 (Box 5.)
  - Nash, F. C., 1944
  - Nearkey, Alezander, 1945
  - Nejelski, Leo, 1948
  - Newberry, Betty, 1942
  - Newman, Bruno, 1944
  - Nichols, Clyde, 1948
  - Nichols, William, 1946
  - Niemo-Niemojowski, Lech, 1941
  - Northrop, F. S. C., 1953
  - Oberholtzer, Edward H., 1943
  - Oliver, Maureen, 1942
  - O'Neal, C. H., 1942
  - Ong, Robert, 1942
  - Ortmann, Loretta, 1942
  - Palmer, L. C., 1942
  - Pangborn, Cyrus, 1959
  - Patterson, Ernest Minor, 1948
  - Pease, Gladys, 1942
  - Pelton, John L., 1942
  - Pereira, Ernie, 1970
  - Perini, Mr., 1967
  - Pettus, W. B., 1942
  - Phoebus, Peggy, 1942
  - Pickford, Mary, 1959-1968
  - Pilling, Bertha, 1942
  - Platt, Harry, 1942
  - Poland, Reginald, 1944
  - Ponsford, Arthur, 1942
  - Pope, Arthur Upman, 1968-1969
  - Pope, Louis, 1942
  - Poteat, Gordon, 1969
  - Powell, Edna, n.d.
  - Price, Harry B., 1943
  - Price, Millard, 1942
  - Prout, F. J., 1946
  - Pruitt, Ida, 1975
  - Purcell, Jean, 1942
  - Qou, Tai-chi, 1941-1952
  - Ralph, Malcolm, 1942
  - Rankin, J. D., 1953
  - Rappoport, Albert, 1949
  - Rea, Ruth, 1942
  - Reidy, David W., 1942
  - Reinisch, F. H., n.d.
  - Reischauer, Edwin O., 1953
  - Reynolds, Louis, 1942
  - Rhine, Larry, 1942
  - Richards, C. F., 1953
  - Richards, Josiah, 1942
  - Richardson, Elsie, 1948
  - Riss, Lillian, 1948
  - Robinson, Mrs. H. W., 1953
  - Rodd, Marcel, 1944
  - Rosenblatt, Sol A., 1944
  - Russel, Bertrand, 1961-1962
  - Saburova, Irina, 1970
  - Sammartino, Dr., 1966
  - Saunders, William, 1943
  - Sayers, Mentana, 1942
  - Schiff, Gunther H., 1945
  - Schuster, M. Lincoln, 1957, 1968
  - Scoville, Ralph C., 1942
  - Scully, Jerry, 1966
  - Seavey, Walter, K., 1942
  - Shapiro, Seymour, 1942
  - Shaw, Kinn-wei, 1944
  - Sheltors, A. L., 1942
  - Sheppard, Emily, 1946
  - Sholar, William J., 1949
  - Sick, Ilse von, 1948
  - Singh, Anup, 1945
  - Skeen, Ruth, 1942
  - Smith, Patricia, n.d.
  - Snow, Edgar and Lois, 1960-1972
  - Snowden, Shirley, 1942
  - Soong, T. V., 1941-1943
  - Stearns, Robert L., 1945
  - Sterling, J. E. Wallace, 1942
  - Stern, Ruth, 1972
  - Stevens, Mary, 1948
  - Stevenson, Mrs. M. J., 1942
  - Stilwell, Alison, 1943
  - Stonier, Tom, 1967 (Box 6.)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, 1942
  - Strassmann, Toni, 1948
  - Street, Jessie M. G., 1964
  - Strong, Ann, 1942
  - Strong, Anna Louise, 1948
  - Strong, Dexter, 1944
  - Sullivan, Donald J., n.d.
  - Suydman, M. R., n.d.
  - Suyun, Han, 1970-1974
  - Sze, Sao-ke Alfred, 1942, 1955
  - Szold, Bernadine, n.d.
  - Sztoleman, Edith F. S., 1942
  - Teel, Ann, 1942
  - Todd, C. C., 1942
  - Tooker, Hugh R., 1942
  - Tretiak, Daniel, 1973
  - Tseng, Y. F. H., 1948
  - Treutheis, Theodor, 1942
  - Turner, Aletha, 1944
  - Turner, Mrs. Frank, n.d.
  - Vetch, H., 1965
  - Viganego, S. J., 1944
  - Walcott, Gregory D., 1952, 1956
  - Wales, Arthur, 1957
  - Walker, Arlie G., n.d.
  - Waller, R. H., 1948
  - Wang, C. Y., 1944
  - Wang, D., 1969
  - Wang, T. P., 1944
  - Warde, Shirley, 1944
  - Watkins, V. S., 1950
  - Watumull, G. J., 1945
  - Wei, T. S., 1969
  - Weil, Leroy, 1953
  - Wells, Edward, 1956
  - Wendell, James, 1943, 1946
  - Weston, Carol, 1942
  - Wheeler, Charles B., 1949
  - White, Margerie, 1970
  - Whitman, Alden, 1970
  - Whitman, Evelyn, 1942
  - William, Maurice, 1949
  - Williams, Raymond Lee, 1942
  - Wilson, Howard, 1947
  - Wilson, Whila, 1942
  - Winn, John J., 1950
  - Winterfeldt, Graefin von, n.d.
  - Wirkler, John E., 1944
  - Wolfe, Jesse, 1942
  - Wood, Maxine, 1949
  - Wong, June, 1942
  - Work, June, 1941
  - Workman, Boyle, 1949
  - Wright, R. L., 1942
  - Wu, Ko-kan, 1968
  - Wu, S. Y., 1968
  - Yousson, Ake E., 1944
  - Zang, Suzanne, 1941
  - Zarbock, James, 1944
  - Zimm, Maurice, 1942
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1942-1966
  - Untitled (Box 7.)
  - "ABC Roundtable," 28 March 1942-27 June 1942, radio news broadcasts, stenciled scripts
  - "All We Are," n.d., typewritten carbon of short story dealing with China during the Japanese invasion of 1937
  - America and China, a New Approach to Asia, 1966, typewritten draft of book
  - "Animals and Their Evolution," n.d., typewritten lecture
  - "Astronomy," n.d., typewritten lecture
  - "Chemistry," n.d., typewritten lecture
  - Chiang Kai-Shek, Asia's Man of Destiny, 1944, typewritten and handwritten draft of book (Box 8.)
  - Chaing Kai-Shek, Asia's Man of Destiny, 1944, typewritten draft of book (Box 9.)
  - "Chiang Kai-Shek in India," n.d., typewritten original of article
  - "The Chinese Are Like That," n.d., typewritten original of article
  - "East Asia in the Modern World," n.d., handwritten notes for lecture
  - "East Asian History and Culture," n.d., handwritten notes for lecture.
  - "Effects of War on Cultural Forces in Asia," n.d., typewritten draft of article
  - The Fabulous Concubine, 1956, typewritten carbon draft of book
  - The Fabulous Concubine, 1956, typewritten original draft of book (Box 10.)
  - The Fabulous Concubine, 1956, typewritten carbon draft of book (Box 11.)
  - The Fabulous Concubine, 1956, handwritten research notes and corrections to the text
  - "From Looking at a Picture," n.d., typewritten carbon draft of article
  - "Genesis of the Book," n.d., typewritten carbon draft for introduction to Chiang Kai-Shek, Asia's Man of Destiny
  - "Hollywood Was No Accident," n.d., typewritten and handwritten drafts of essay on the Changs' arrival in the United States in 1941
  - "How the Milky Way Came To Be," 1947, typewritten drafts of article
  - "How to Achieve World Peace," n.d., typewritten draft of speech delivered in Santa Rosa in 1950
  - "Human Beings and Their Evolution," n.d., typewritten original notes for lecture
  - "The Human Body," n.d., typewritten original notes for lecture
  - "The Human Nervous System and Brain," n.d., typewritten original notes for lecture
  - "Humanism: It's Meaning and Evolution," 1967, photocopy of typewritten draft
  - "Is There a Secret in China's Resistance," n.d., typewritten carbon draft of article (Box 12.)
  - "Is There No Remedy," n.d., typewritten draft of article
  - "Japanese and Indian Philosophy," n.d., handwritten original notes for lectures
  - Letters From a Chinese Diplomat, 1948, handwritten and typewritten original drafts of book
  - "The Marshall Mission to China," n.d., typewritten original and carbon draft of article
  - "Memorandum on the Need for Centralizing Publicity in the USA," n.d., typewritten carbon of memorandum
  - "Memorandum on the Solution of the Chinese Question," n.d., typewritten original of memorandum
  - "Modern Geography," n.d., typewritten original of lecture
  - "The Nature of Philosophy," n.d., typewritten original of lecture
  - "The Nature of Science," n.d., typewritten original of notes for lecture
  - "New Frontier in Asia," n.d., handwritten draft of unpublished book
  - "The Problem of Lasting Peace," n.d., typewritten original and carbon draft of article
  - "Oriental Philosophy," 1962-1963, handwritten original notes for lecture
  - "The Origin and Nature of Life," n.d., typewritten original notes for lecture
  - "Our Responsibility after the War," 31 May 1942, Baccalaureate Address given at Washington State College, handwritten and typewritten drafts of speech
  - "Physics," n.d., typewritten original of notes for lecture
  - "Plants and Their Evolution," n.d., typewritten original of notes for lecture
  - "Post-War Reconstruction in China," n.d., typewritten carbon draft of article
  - "Quo Tai-chi as China's New Foreign Minister," n.d., typewritten original of article
  - "Radio Broadcast News Commentary," 16 March 1942-30 March 1942, typewritten originals of radio scripts
  - "Radio Broadcast News Commentary," 1 April 1942-15 September 1942, typewritten originals of radio scripts (Box 13.)
  - "The Responsibilities of American Youth," n.d., handwritten draft of article
  - "Shanghai Phoenix," n.d., typewritten carbon draft of unpublished book dealing with events in China during the period 1937-1940
  - "Sino-British Cultural Relationship," n.d., typewritten carbon draft of broadcast speech
  - "Some Polish Reminscences," n.d., typewritten carbon draft of essay detailing Chang Hsin Hai's experiences in Poland from 1933 until 1937
  - "Speech on the Republican Party Platform," 22 April 1942, ditto text of speech given to meeting of the Republican National Committee
  - "The Story of Eastern Philosophy," n.d., handwritten notes for lecture or publication
  - "To Sin and Be Sinned Against," n.d., typewritten original of article submitted to This Week Magazine
  - "Western Literature and Culture," n.d., handwritten notes for lectures
  - "What to Buy with Your Money," n.d., typewritten original draft of article
  - "Whither Chungking?" n.d., typewritten carbon draft of article
  - Within the Four Seas, 1958, typewritten draft, and annotated galley proofs of book (Box 14.)
  - "You Must Take What You Give," n.d., typewritten original draft of article
  - Various unprocessed note cards bearing notes on Western and Oriental culture, literature, and history (Box 15.)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1941-1972
  - American Cancer Society Inc., 1959 (Box 16.)
  - Asia Pacific Seminar, 1966
  - Babbitt, Irving, n.d.
  - "Battle of China," n.d., United States Army Orientation Film Photographic Scenario
  - Biographic file
  - Chang, Mrs. Siang-mei Rosalynde, n.d.
  - Chang, Yian, n.d.
  - Chen, Che-yu, "Memoir of My Life with Chiang Kai-Shek," n.d.
  - China
    - Foreign Relations with United States
    - History
    - Literature
  - Chinese News Service, 1943
  - Committee for a New China Policy, 1972
  - Cordier, Henri, Essai d'une Bibliographie des Ouvrages Publies en Chine Les Europeens au XVIIe et XVIIIe Sciele, 1883 (Box 17.)
  - Hu Shih, China Too Is Fighting to Defend a Way of Life, 1942
  - Institute of Current World Affairs, 1967
  - International Conference for Solidarity with the People of Vietnam Against U.S. Aggression, 1964
  - Jefferson, Thomas, 1957
  - Lamumba, Patrice, 1960
  - New York State Faculty Seminar on International Politics of Southeast Asia, 1965
  - "The Pacific Story," n.d., radio script
  - Philosophy
    - Chinese
    - Oriental
  - Suennens, Leon Joseph, Cardinal, 1963
  - Soka Gakkai, 1962
  - Soviet Central Asia, n.d.
  - Tiao Yu Tai Islands, 1971
  - United States of America, Foreign relations with China
  - United Nations General Assembly, 1959, 1964
- MISCELLANY
  - Various unprocessed article reprints and newspaper clippings (Box 18.-19.)